<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Pulsar Neighborhood</title><link>https://pulsar-neighborhood.com/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Pulsar Neighborhood</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 15:54:13 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pulsar-neighborhood.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Apache Pulsar and Machine Learning</title><link>https://pulsar-neighborhood.com/articles/apache-pulsar-and-machine-learning/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 15:54:13 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://pulsar-neighborhood.com/articles/apache-pulsar-and-machine-learning/</guid><description>Simba Khadder shared his insights on why Pulsar Distributed Messaging system and its separation of storage and brokerage layers are great fit for AI/ML applications.</description></item><item><title>Happenings in the Pulsar Neighborhood Feb '22</title><link>https://pulsar-neighborhood.com/articles/happenings-in-the-pulsar-neighborhood-feb-22/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 10:58:45 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://pulsar-neighborhood.com/articles/happenings-in-the-pulsar-neighborhood-feb-22/</guid><description>For this issue, a new PMC member, 2 new committers, a call to help improve the quality of the code, a meetup in Italian, and a new and improved home page coming soon. Plus our normal features of a Stack Overflow question and some monthly community stats.</description></item><item><title>Apache Pulsar Transactions API Deep Dives</title><link>https://pulsar-neighborhood.com/articles/apache-pulsar-transactions-api-deep-dives/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 14:55:27 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://pulsar-neighborhood.com/articles/apache-pulsar-transactions-api-deep-dives/</guid><description>Transactions are an API in Apache Pulsar that enables atomic operations among pulsar consumers and producers. This talk covers the motivating factors for Transactions in a system like Apache Pulsar, deep dives into the transactions API, and walks through some examples of using Transactions with the pulsar4s client.</description></item><item><title>Happenings in the Pulsar Neighborhood Jan 22</title><link>https://pulsar-neighborhood.com/articles/happenings-in-the-pulsar-neighborhood-jan-22/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 15:32:45 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://pulsar-neighborhood.com/articles/happenings-in-the-pulsar-neighborhood-jan-22/</guid><description>For this issue, we have some end of the year stats, Log4j updates, a new PMC member, and lots of talks. Plus our normal features of a Stack Overflow question and some monthly community stats.</description></item><item><title>[Video] Internals of Stream Processing</title><link>https://pulsar-neighborhood.com/articles/internals-of-stream-processing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 15:36:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://pulsar-neighborhood.com/articles/internals-of-stream-processing/</guid><description>Stream Processing Systems (SPSs) are an integral part of modern data-intensive companies. In a world where streams are becoming king, they are commonly employed for much more than data analytics. Yet, most of developers only use them and have never dove deep into the internals of the system.</description></item><item><title>[Video] Using Open Source Software to improve Streaming on the Edge</title><link>https://pulsar-neighborhood.com/articles/using-open-source-software-to-improve-streaming-on-the-edge/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 15:39:51 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://pulsar-neighborhood.com/articles/using-open-source-software-to-improve-streaming-on-the-edge/</guid><description>IoT devices are expected to number in the billions, each device enabled by one or more sensors, generating data about the device and its surrounding environment. Analyzing this data using machine learning (ML)/Artificial Intelligence (AI) models, for example, frequently requires transferring this data to the cloud.</description></item><item><title>Apache Bookkeeper and Apache Zookeeper for Apache Pulsar</title><link>https://pulsar-neighborhood.com/articles/apache-bookkeeper-and-apache-zookeeper-for-apache-pulsar/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 15:42:47 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://pulsar-neighborhood.com/articles/apache-bookkeeper-and-apache-zookeeper-for-apache-pulsar/</guid><description>Enrico Olivelli speaks to the Japan Apache Pulsar User Group about how Apache Pulsar uses Apache ZooKeeper and Apache BookKeeper, with a particular focus on how Pulsar guarantees consistency even in spite of common failures in distributed systems.</description></item><item><title>[Video] Apache Pulsar Deep Dive an End-to-End View of the Data Flow</title><link>https://pulsar-neighborhood.com/articles/apache-pulsar-deep-dive-an-end-to-end-view-of-the-data-flow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 15:51:42 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://pulsar-neighborhood.com/articles/apache-pulsar-deep-dive-an-end-to-end-view-of-the-data-flow/</guid><description>Enrico Olivelli gives us a tour of how data moves from the Producer to the Consumer.</description></item><item><title>[Video] Leveraging Pulsar's Next Gen Streaming Capabilities from a JavaEE Application</title><link>https://pulsar-neighborhood.com/articles/leveraging-pulsars-next-gen-streaming-capabilities-from-a-javaee-application/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 15:57:41 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://pulsar-neighborhood.com/articles/leveraging-pulsars-next-gen-streaming-capabilities-from-a-javaee-application/</guid><description>In this session you will see how to use Pulsar in a JakartaEE Web Application deployed on Apache TomEE via the JMS/EJB API, without installing any additional components to your cluster.</description></item><item><title>Running Apache Pulsar in Multiple Regions</title><link>https://pulsar-neighborhood.com/articles/running-apache-pulsar-in-multiple-regions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 16:00:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://pulsar-neighborhood.com/articles/running-apache-pulsar-in-multiple-regions/</guid><description>Zeke Dean walks us through how to run Apache Pulsar in multiple regions</description></item><item><title/><link>https://pulsar-neighborhood.com/spotlight/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pulsar-neighborhood.com/spotlight/</guid><description>David has been a technologist for longer than he will admit. He’s been a part of enterprise sales, developer advocacy, and open source support for years. He’s a father and a husband surrounded by horses and bourbon in Louisville, Kentucky. While he would love to share an impressive list of hobbies and leisurely activities, the truth is he’s either in dad mode or writing code. Learn more here[https://linkedin.com/in/ddieruf].</description></item></channel></rss>